#### Hardi Yanto

Bukittinggi 26125| https://www.linkedin.com/in/hardiyantoo | +685215255091 | hhardiyanto97@gmail.com

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

As a public administration bachelor, that interest on social media specialist, team management and public speaker, specially handling relation between edu techgroup and education department, branding, business project management and operational strategy with growth mindset. Has skill on graphic design, people management, business management, and taks management with result increase small business branding and I very fascinated enter the world of customer relation officer.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

# PT. Ruang Raya Indonesia

Account Manager (Ocktober 2022 - Desember 2022)

- Mapping more than 200 schools based on categories using technical skill, SPSS and Google tools based on the distance and economic level of the customer.
- Handle more than 100 people in charge of negotiating cooperation in the form of consultative sales and product bug buying. Handle 8 sales by meeting the needs of 3 class audiences in 1 week.
- Managed and Lobbying more than three people in charge to be able to launch company programs, seminars, consultations, and bug buying Develop long-term client relationships with 3
  different districts and 3 different cities.
- Prepare ideas, present concepts, and make actionable proposals. Every week, bug buying and delivering plans to close business to business with 20 departments.
- Collaborate with two divisions, an academic team, and an internal team to ensure the smooth operation of projects and the achievement of deadlines in the proposal and national award for MAN 2 Bukittinggi.

## Kuma Ruma Foo & Coo Enthusiast

## Business Development (August 2022 - January 2023)

- Designed Kumaruma foo & foo enthusiast branding campaign concept, achieved soft opening on november 2022.
- Field observations in determining the location, target market, brand marketing, and reducing competitor determination.
- Handled and compiled coffeeshop operational standards ranging from hiring, internal auditing, management, and overall operation.
- Using digital marketing in determining the potential target market Prepare barista and waitress job descriptions to comply with SOP and internal audit programs.
- Controlling customer development rate with CAC techniques and business administration Manage employee workfow using the SPSS System including audit assignment and maintenance, achieved customer growth with 50 cups everyday.

## PT. Ruang Raya Indonesia

## Marketing Executive (April 2022 - Present)

- Complete more than 3 classes in 1 week with consultative selling and EIMBC technique.
- Accommodating more than 1000 data leads into Google spreadsheets with deadlines.

- Handle more than 120 students in one week with different learning problems and adjust them based on the right product using communication skill.
- Handled and process more than 30 data using email and WhatsApp blast each 1 day
- Handling SNBT 2023 Tryout Seminar with 200 Parents of Students at Man 1 City of Bukittinggi Suggesting changes in customer needs to improve brand awareness, and achieved high motivation from students at MAN 1 Bukittinggi to use the product Ruang Belajar
- Manage action calls with 100 data leads each month on Crm Ruangguru Managed cluster achievement through consultative selling and achieved the best performance in Ruangguru regional Sumbagteng II with revenue of more than Rp 30.000.000 in less than a month.

#### **EDUCATION**

Padang State University

Bachelors Public Administration (August 2017 - August 2021, IPK 3.43/4.00)

- Learned and application basic leadership, analytic and public speaking as overview leadership management, POAC in action, team building and public speaking.
- Learned and application the tools for analysis statistic such as SPSS, SAS/STAT dan Stata.
- Obtained a bachelor's degree with cum laude with honors Successfully researched and formulated service problems at the immigration ofce class II Non TPI Agam during the covid 19 pandemic.

## **PROJECTS**

Business Development (August 2022 - January 2023)

- Create and manage the process of observation, negotiating, and presenting, coffee shop proposals.
- Performed brand awareness and create social media champaign for kumaruma foo & coo enthusiast
- Handled 5 crew team with fun and humanity and get positive feedback from customer with online customer statisfaction.

## **SKILLS**

Public Speaking (Intermediate), Internal Auditor (Intermediate), Management (Beginner), Public Relation (Beginner), Costumer Satisfactions (Beginner), Copy Writing (Beginner), Customer Orientied (Beginner), Social media marketing and social media ads content (Beginner), Microsoft ofce tools (Intermediate), Statistical Product service and solution (Beginner), CRM, Google Tools & Mapping (Beginner).

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Get to know marketing strategy using key opinion leader Dibimbing.id January 2022 Participate in training programs and digital marketing key opinion leaders consisting of engagement, operational standards, inuencer selection grids and basic understanding of event organizers.

Certificate Of Appreciation 2<sup>nd</sup> place best field education consultant Region Sumbagteng II during July – August 2022